At this point, we've established that we need to be looking at our metrics daily.
现在 我们已经取得了共识 即每天都要关注指标
Not every analytics project is going to be about a specific initiative,
不是每个分析项目都只关注某个特定的目标
you might be running many initiatives and you
你可能有多个目标并行
need to be capturing the health of your marketing.
然后你需要全局关注市场营销的健康
So to get there,
因此
let's talk about the five critical areas to any business
我们来介绍用户生命周期中的 5 个重要环节
regardless of where you're at and what you're trying to capture.
不管你处在哪个行业 或者你需要获取什么数据 这个模型都适用
First, we have acquisition.
第一个环节 用户获取 (Acquisition)
This is the process of converting your customer.
在这个步骤 你的目标是转化用户
The customer comes in from any number of channels,
用户可能会从各种渠道来
and once they arrive,
一旦他们触达到了
we move to activation.
我们就转移到下一个环节 用户激活 (Activation)
This is users having a good first-time experience.
在这个环节 我们希望给用户留下好的首次体验
From here, we have retention.
再然后 就是用户留存（Retention）的环节
This is the act of keeping that customer,
即 如何留存客户
finding ways to make sure that they don't leave your experience.
使用各种方法避免用户流失
Then we have referral.
第四 自传播 (Refer) 环节
These are customers telling their friends.
在这个环节 用户会把你的品牌推荐给其他人
From here, we have a revenue,
最后 获取营收 (Revenue) 环节
and that's the money you are bringing in.
在这个环节 我们产生了收入
Now this looks close to our funnel with a few twists,
这个看起来其实有点像漏斗 只不过有一些区别
but Dave McClure, venture capitalists and angel investor,
Dave McClure 知名风险投资家和天使投资人
described these areas as the pirate metrics,
将这五个环节称之为 海盗模型（pirate metrics）
named because when you take the first letter of each of the stages,
原因是因为如果你把这五个环节的英文首字母连起来
it sounds well, like a pirate.
发音就很像海盗的常用语
The goal is to identify a key metric from
我们需要根据我们的业务目标来找到和确认
each of those areas depending on what your business objective is.
这五个环节的关键指标分别是什么
For a brand new product just entering the market,
对于刚进入市场的全新产品
you can get away with focusing on qualitative metrics.
你可以使用一些定性指标
For acquisition, this is,
比如在用户获取环节 就是
how our customers finding us?
客户找到我们的途径
For activation, what are our customers saying?
对于用户激活环节 就是 客户对我们的评价是什么
Retention, why are customers leaving or why aren't they leaving?
对于用户留存环节 就是 为什么用户会流失或者选择我们
What's keeping them around? For referral,
什么吸引了用户的留存？对于自传播环节
would customers share this with their friends?
就是 用户是否会与朋友分享
For revenue, are we making money?
对于获取营收环节 就是 我们是否盈利？
Now, if you were studying those metrics daily,
如果你每天都关注这些指标
you'd have a very good pulse on the health of your business.
那么 你对业务的健康度应该就了如指掌了
Now there's no actual qualitative data behind them,
虽然可能这些问题的答案并不是可量化的数据
but it is a good sense as you start out.
但是对于一个全新产品 这些问题是个良好的开端
As you move towards actually having a product in the market,
随着你的产品日趋成熟
you want to start looking at the foundational qualitative metrics.
你应该关注一些基本的量化指标
These are the measurements that you want to be able to report on daily,
通过这些指标以及他们背后的量化数据 你可以随时汇报
as they will really describe in a qualitative sense the health of your business.
你的业务是否正常运营
For acquisition, this could be your number of conversions.
比如 对于用户获取环节 可以是用户转化量
This will demonstrate how your business is doing,
用户转化量可以告诉你
whether you're growing or whether the trend is declining.
你的业务是否在扩张还是在缩减
Now, if you aren't measuring conversions,
如果你不想用转化量
this could be leads for example or simply visit.
也可以用潜在客户数量 (leads) 或者访问量
Whatever the objective is for your business,
不管业务目标是什么
you will factor into that daily metric.
都应该将用户获取环节的指标考虑进去
From here, it's activation.
然后是用户激活
This is the information around how much time someone is spending in your product,
比如 用户在你的产品页面的停留时间
your customer support ticket volume,
客户售后工单数量
areas of your metrics that demonstrate what is happening to get that customer activated.
总之 是能展现出用户被如何激活的一些指标
Next, you want to understand what's going on with retention.
接下来 你需要了解用户留存情况
What's your churn rate?
客户流失率是多少？
Now sometimes retention data doesn't change all that much.
有时候客户流失率比较稳定 变化不大
But it's important that you have a pulse on it because if there was
但是你仍然应该有个大致的了解
a large uptick in customers that were canceling for example,
这样如果有大批客户退订的话
you know that you have a problem.
你就会知道出现了问题
These metrics are very important because they
这些指标非常重要 因为它们是
indicate that there is a problem in the health of your business,
业务是否正常运营的表征
and that's why we look at them daily.
这也是为什么我们需要每天都关注这些指标
If we waited too long,
如果等很长时间才去观察
we'd miss something important.
我们可能会错失一些重要的信息
From here, we look at referral and this could be conversions or
接下来 我们关注自传播 这里可以是推荐渠道的转化率
whatever other activation or acquisition data by this referral source.
或者用户获取和激活情况
We look at this because we want to understand where that customer is coming from.
关注这个主要是想了解用户的来源渠道都是什么
If we see a large upswing in referrals,
如果看到自传播的推荐数量大幅上升
we know we have something going on.
我们就会知道有情况发生
Finally, revenue.
最后 获取营收
It's important that we always understand how much money the businesses bringing in.
了解企业的盈利情况 非常重要
Now you might zoom these analytics in.
你可能会想细分营收
For example, it might be the revenue that you're
比如 关注你负责的业务的营收
particularly responsible for or it could be the revenue of the whole business.
还是公司的整体营收
But it's important that you understand this in a time-frame that makes sense.
另外 你可以关注固定的、合理的时间段内的营收情况
You could be looking at revenue by day over the last seven days,
比如过去一周每天的营收情况
over the last 30 days or the trend for what's going to happen that month.
或者过去一个月的 以及趋势
Now, once you've started to invest in actual marketing spend,
你一旦开始投资实际的市场开销
you want to increase your focus and start layering in more metrics.
就需要扩大你的关注范围 考虑更多的指标
For acquisition, you might bring in your conversion rate and your cost per acquisition.
比如 对于用户获取 你需要考虑转化率以及每次获取成本 CPA
This is important because you want to understand how many customers are
这个很重要 因为你不但要知道有多少用户
arriving for the campaigns that you're
因为你的市场活动成功转化
creating and how much you're spending to bring in those customers.
而且要知道你为了获取这些用户而花费的成本是多少
Typically, we have a intense focus on that cost per acquisition.
通常 我们都会非常关注 CPA
That's a number that we always want to be bringing down.
因为我们的业务目标是降低 CPA
The more customers we can bring in for less money, the better.
每次获取成本越低 越好
So it's important to have a pulse on that.
所以对于 CPA 情况有个大致的了解 是很重要的
For activation, now we're starting to look at our customer lifetime value.
对于用户激活 我们可以开始关注客户终身价值 LTV
We want that number to be going up,
这个数字要越高 越好
we're finding ways to influence how valuable this customer is.
我们应该要尝试各种方式来影响客户的终身价值
If that value is dropping, we have a problem.
如果 LTV 下降 问题就大了
For retention, this is again typically
对于用户留存 通常就是关注流失率
a churn rate but we can also look at how much we're recapturing.
但是也可以关注有多少用户被重新"捞"回来
So as we mature,
随着产品的成熟
we are going to be looking at ways that we take customers that are
我们会需要关注那些已流失
canceling or attempting to cancel and recapture them.
或者可能流失的用户 然后重新赢回他们
We're also looking at our email open rates,
还有就是 邮件打开率
because this helps identify the health of our messaging and whether we're resonating.
这个指标体现了我们传达信息的效率
As you look at these metrics daily,
如果你每天关注这个指标
you get a good sense of the health of your communication with your existing customers.
你就会知道你是否与你的用户群保持良好的沟通
For referral, we might have an affiliate program that we're running.
对于自传播 我们可能会想要开展一个附属项目
So we'd want to check in on that growth rate.
然后关注这个项目的增长情况
Another piece of data that can change by day,
某些指标可能每天都在变化
an affiliate could launch something new that
通过开展这个附属项目 这个渠道的一些指标
dramatically changes what happens in that channel.
可能会发生巨大的改变
For revenue, well, we might start looking at something called our compound monthly or
对于获取营收 我们可以关注
our compound annual growth rate which essentially helps
月均或者年均复合增长率 可以帮助我们了解
us understand how we're trending against a baseline.
当前情况对于某个基准呈现了怎样的趋势
Your key metrics should act as the vital signs to help you understand
综上 你的关键指标应该是你了解总体产品情况
the overall health of your product and serve to
的关键性表征 而且可以帮助你判断
influence the changes that you make to your marketing strategy.
是否需要对营销策略做出改变
Use the pirate metrics model as
因此 建议你使用海盗模型来自查
a simple framework to see if you're looking at your most important metrics,
是否有关注最重要的指标
and doing so everyday.
以及是否有每天都在关注